So, I said the Axios made it easier to
make um post, put, patch, and delete
requests in the last video, and I said
I'd show you how to use them here. In
order to do that, I spun up an API and a
REST API, and it just listens and then
when it gets a get request, it returns
the data inside of this name. If it gets
a post request, it adds the data. If it
gets a put request or a patch request,
it edits the data. And if it gets a
delete request, it deletes the data. So
um let's go ahead and add a data. So if
I say axiospost
and then it says where do I want to post
to? Well my
um API is running locally on localhost
and it's running on localhost 5000names.
What do I want to send it? Well, I want
to send it a new name and I'm going to
put my name in. If I save this, it runs
my code. And now I can see in the DBJ
JSON I have my name which is great. So
now we have created a resource. Um
what if we want to get the resource? So
we could say get
and then do then take the result data
take the result and console.log
result.data.
And if we log it, we can see we got back
both items that we wanted.
Well, what if we wanted to update one of
the items? Well, there's two ways to do
that. There's put and there's patch. Um,
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to
say I want you to go out and edit the
data. So, I'm going to say put and then
it needs to know which one I want to
edit. To do that, I put a slash on the
end and then I find the ID. In this
case, let's edit the ID I just made of
CE D0 for my name. So we'll do C E D0.
And then what we need to do is we need
to tell it what we want to update. So
now let's set my name equal to my full
name. If I save that and I come over
here, you can see it updated my full
name, but it left the other record
alone.
Um, and then if I wanted to delete my
name, I could call the delete method,
find my name,
and delete it, and it's gone. And so,
you can see that Axios made it super
simple to do um, post, put, and delete.
And all you had to do was call the right
keyword and change the URL slightly.